MAHMOUD KAROUT

 $BEIRUT, LEBANON \mid P: +961\ 70963955 \mid mahmoudtkarout@gmail.com \mid linkedin.com/in/mahmoudkarout \mid Portfolio:www.mahmoudkarout.com$

SUMMARY

Software developer with 3+ years experience participating in the complete product development lifecycle of successfully launched applications and aiming to secure a new opportunity where to mobilize my skills acquired through past experiences and self-study, towards advancing your organisation's growth. In previous roles, was able to optimize apps by 50%, and led a team of 4 people to deliver a project that resulted a reported 60% increase in the clients productivity

EXPERIENCE

ITXI - Beirut, Lebanon

Mobile Developer

Jun 2020 – Present

- Deployed 2 cross-platform mobile applications in a test-driven development TDD process
- Optimized apps to perform 50% faster and more efficiently when computing demanding functions
- Planned and led the API integration procedure and state management in each application
- Contributed in the Internationalization and Localization process for more than 15 languages
- Implemented automated unit testing with 90% code coverage using sonarCloud
- Wrote and updated technical documents on Confluence
- Coached new developers on the CI/CD methodology and tools
- Used Atlassian (BitBucket, JIRA) and Google Suite environments for project management

Entrepreneur Venture - Beirut, Lebanon

Full Stack Developer

Jun 2018 - Jan 2019

- Guided a team of 4 developers to build a company directory website for the MENA region
- Provided support and leadership in critical production support issue resolution
- Designed the application's user interface and user experience
- Assisted the team in designing the database to be well-organized and most efficient
- Conducted code reviews to ensure the delivery of high quality standards project

American University of Beirut - Beirut, Lebanon

Full Stack Developer

Jan 2018 - May 2018

- Managed a team of 4 students to operate in agile to digitize a department's workflow
- Designed the UI/UX of the application based on the customer's requirements.
- Created a dashboard that keeps track of incoming and old products in the warehouse
- Achieved a reported 60% increase in productivity and maintainability from the client

EDUCATION

AMERICAN UNIVERSITY OF BEIRUT - Beirut, Lebanon

Sept 2016 – Jan 2020

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Main CS courses: Data Structure, Software Architecture, Advanced Programming

PROJECTS

ADVERSARIAL MACHINE LEARNING - Beirut, Lebanon

Software Developer & Researcher

Jan 2019 - May 2019

- Researched and Developed an adversarial machine learning algorithm
- Challenged Google's "TensorFlow" image classifier by generating a 75% undetectable patches
- Accepted as a full paper to the IEEE AICCSA 2019 in Abu Dhabi

SKILLS

Programming Languages: C#, HTML5 / CSS, Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL

Frameworks: ASP.net, React Native (2+ years), ReactJs (2+ years)

Environments: NodeJS

Tools & Platforms: Android Studio, Firebase, GitHub/BitBucket, Microsoft Visual Studio, Postman

Soft Skill: Leadership, Teamwork, Empathy, Communication, Critical Thinking

Languages: English, French, and Arabic (Fluent in reading, writing and speaking)